

## Profile

Result-oriented individual with strong communication and collaborative skills. I bring experience with object-oriented design, the ability to code with a variety of languages, experience with agile and scrum methodologies, and a strong and reliable work ethic.

## Employment History

## Associate Software Engineer at Verint | Remote, CA

August 2022 — Present

- Led a small project team to design and implement a configuration page for our Web UI Messenger using React; coordinated tasks and documentation through JIRA and Confluence, resulting in enhanced user customization and improved user experience.
- Selected for an elite team to review and assess a newly acquired company's codebase; provided critical feedback, addressed code errors, and introduced new unit tests using TypeScript, Jest, Vue Test Utils, and Vitest, enhancing software quality and integration robustness.
- Elevated as a key member of the infrastructure team, enhancing our B2B application using Vue, TypeScript, Vuetify, Axios, and Pinia; additionally, developed proxy script packages, streamlining and accelerating the onboarding process for new users.

#### Senior Customer Specialist at CarMax | Pleasant Hill, CA

June 2019 — August 2022

- Spearheaded store operations, emphasizing sales process and budget management, resulting in increased profitability, improved customer satisfaction, and the development of associates' skills, showcasing strong leadership and management abilities.
- Oversaw vendor activities, ensuring excellent customer service and efficient administration per contracts and performance guarantees, demonstrating strong project management skills.
- Led the team in setting strategy for the store, providing team members with a clear vision, direction, and motivation, highlighting strong communication and leadership skills.

### Software Developer at Peritik Jewelry | Bay Point, CA

December 2018 — April 2019

- Led the redesign of a website, focusing on improving customer engagement and navigation while also integrating Shopify CRM for better control of customer orders and data.
- Played a pivotal role in every aspect of the product development process, from ideation to development and improvement, resulting in features

#### **Details**

Concord, CA, 94521

925-726-6403

gonzalezhilariojose@gmail.com

#### Links

https://hilario.io https://github.com/Hilarioo https://www.linkedin.com/in/ hilariooo/

#### Skills

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe XD

AJAX

**Amazon Web Services** 

Axios

Azure

CI/CD

Confluence

C++

**DOM Manipulation** 

Express.js

Figma

Git

HTML & CSS

il8n

Jira

Java

JavaScript

Jest

jQuery

Pinia

that reached over 15,000 monthly users, showcasing strong skills in front-end development and design.

 Reduced customer support requests by 30% by implementing ManyChat, automating Facebook messaging to provide a more efficient and streamlined customer experience.

## Coding Instructor at Code 4 Kids | Brentwood, CA

August 2017 — June 2018

- Led the planning and execution of comprehensive lesson plans and instructional activities for 4-5th grade students, tailored to individual students' proficiency in computers and programming.
- Developed and implemented an engaging after-school curriculum that introduced students to the basics of programming, emphasized its importance, and culminated in a small project using HTML and CSS, showcasing strong skills in front-end development and design.
- Maintained clear and consistent communication with parents regarding student progress, goals, and any potential barriers to success, utilizing multiple preferred methods of communication such as email and SMS.

# Projects

## **Weather App**

July 2022

- Designed and developed a responsive weather web app that allows users to view current and future weather conditions based on location, leveraging user IP addresses to provide localized data.
- Implemented using: React, Typescript, Context API, Axios, Date-fns, Jest, NodeJS, and MaterialUI

## **Donut Music**

May 2022

- full-stack web application featuring a violin, guitar, drums, and flute as
  instruments and four unique visualizers. Our visualizers react to the amps,
  hertz, and/or speed of the song or key playing.
- Implemented using: TypeScript, React + Redux, Node.js, p5.js, tone.js, socket.io, and sqlite3

### **Recipe IOS App**

January 2022

- Design and implement a recipe app allowing users to create an account, and find new recipes to cook at random or by genre.
- Implemented using: Swift, SwiftUI, Firebase Auth, SpoonacularAPI, and Xcode

#### **Portfolio Website**

June 2021 - present

- Design and implement a dynamic mobile-first website to display achievements and information about me and my projects.
- Implemented using: HTML5, CSS, Vanilla Javascript, DOM Manipulation, and Netlify

Python

Markdown

MongoDB

MUI

Node.js

React

**REST API** 

SQL

Socket IO

Swift

Tailwind CSS

**Testing Library** 

Typescript

Vite

Vitest

**Vue Test Utils** 

Vue 3

Vuetify

Xcode

#### Languages

English

Spanish

## **Talent Pipeline Web App**

January 2021

- Develop and modularize reactJS components including prop and state handling for efficient build optimization and re-usability using Agile Methodologies
- Deploy NodeJS application on AWS EC2 Instance with GitHub
- Led responsive design created with Figma and Adobe Illustrator following Material Design Guidelines
- Implemented using: AWS, Bcrypt, Bootstrap, CSS, Cookie-Parser, Express, Javascript ES6, MySQL, NodeJS, and ReactJS

## **Multi-User Messaging Web App**

January 2020

- Develop a responsive web app that allows users to create an account and message groups of people like Discord
- Integrate asynchronous HTTP requests to REST endpoints to perform CRUD operations with the backend using Axios (a lightweight HTTP client based on the XMLHttpRequests service)
- Implemented using: Axios, JQuery, Java, JavaScript, MongoDB, NodeJS, React-Dom, React

### **Photo Management Web App**

January 2020

- Design responsive user interface and features using AdobeXD and Adobe
  Illustrator
- Develop a responsive web app that allows users to create an account, comment, search and upload images
- Implemented using: Axios, Bcrypt, ExpressJS, Heroku, HTML5/CSS, Javascript, MySQL, NodeJS, and Passport

## Education

**B.S Computer Science, San Francisco State University, San Francisco**August 2019 — May 2022

A.S Mathematics & Physics , Los Medanos College, Pittsburg

August 2015 — May 2017